hey what's up Andrew Kramer here for
嘿，大家好，我是Andrew Kramer，来自
videocopilot net and welcome back to
videocopilot.net，欢迎回到
another very exciting tutorial today
今天的精彩教程。今天
we're going to take a look at creating
我们将学习如何在After Effects中创建
some advanced electricity effects inside
一些高级的闪电特效。
of After Effects this one's going to be
这将会
a lot of fun so let's go and take a look
非常有趣，让我们来看看
at what we're going to be creating
我们将要创建什么。
[Music]
[音乐]
alright so there's a lot of cool things
好的，我们将探索很多很酷的东西，
we're going to be exploring and a lot of
并将许多
different techniques that we're going to
不同的技巧
be combining together so lets going to
结合起来。让我们
take a look at a few of the different
来看几个不同的
setups so here I have an example where
设置。这里有一个例子，
the Lightning is reflecting off of the
闪电在
surface and each time it touches the
表面反射，每次接触
ground it's creating sort of an
地面都会形成一个
interactive contact point so we're going
交互式的接触点。我们将
to take a look at setting up the look of
学习如何设置闪电的外观，
the Lightning and we're also going to be
并学习一些
taking a look at tips to make the
技巧，使
Lightning look more organic and
闪电看起来更自然、更
integrated and create a really nice soft
融入环境，并创造出柔和的
glow and the cool thing about this is
光晕。这个特效的妙处在于
that it's dynamic so we don't have to
它是动态的，所以我们不需要
custom draw any of the reflections and
自定义绘制任何反射。
as you can see in this example same kind
正如你在这个例子中看到的，
of thing but what I can do is I can open
情况类似，但我可以
up the comp with my lightning and just
打开带有闪电效果的合成，
to show you really quickly I can go to
快速演示一下，我可以找到
one of the Lightning effects change the
一个闪电效果，更改
color and it will update in the final
颜色，最终合成中的颜色就会更新。
comp and you can actually play it back
你可以回放，
in the color of the reflection changes
看到反射颜色的变化，
so it's very dynamic and works really
非常动态，效果也很好。好了，就到这里。接下来
quick tip we're going to look at is
我们要介绍的另一个小技巧是
using the source material to influence
利用源素材来影响
the reflection so you can see in this
反射。在这个
example we're actually using some of the
例子中，我们实际上使用了
texture from the original plate to
原始素材中的一些纹理来
influence the reflections intensity so
影响反射强度。我会向
I'll show you some cool tips for
你展示一些控制反射强度的实用技巧。在这里，你可以看到
see how it's interacting with the
它是如何与背景互动的。
I think electricity effects are really
我认为电力效果非常
cool you seem in a lot of great movies
酷，你会在很多优秀的电影中
you know see that scene in Back to the
看到它，比如《回到未来》里的那个场景
[Music]
[音乐]，
electricians traveling down the line and
电工沿着电线移动，结果电
you know killed that kid is one of
死了那个孩子。这是
Steven Spielberg's best movies they like
史蒂文·斯皮尔伯格最棒的电影之一，他们喜欢
that money now another really cool
那种效果。另一个很酷的
example is creating this subsurface
例子是为云层创建次表面
scattering effect for the clouds and
散射效果，
this is a really fun and really powerful
这是一种非常有趣且强大的
technique so definitely pay attention to
技巧，所以一定要注意。
this one and then we're also going to
接下来，我们还要
take a look at adding some electrical
看看如何给
effects to a text or to a logo and you
文字或logo添加一些电光效果。你
can see that it interacts with the
可以看到，它与
contours in a really nice realistic way
轮廓的互动非常逼真，效果很棒。仔细
so take a look at that and then finally
看看。最后，
we're going to take a look at this
我们要学习一种
technique where we can actually control
可以控制
the direction of the lightning in this
闪电方向​​的技术。在这个
case we're kind of have like a reverse
例子中，我们实现了一种类似反
gravity effect so it's a really cool
重力的效果，这是一种非常酷的
technique for giving your lightning a
技巧，可以控制闪电的
direction all right so we've got a lot
方向。好了，我们有很多
of fun stuff to do and of course I'll
有趣的东西要做。当然，我会尽量
minimum now I will admit I went on
少用电光相关的双关语。我承认，我上
Google and I did a search for electrical
谷歌搜索了一下电光相关的双关语，
shocking number of results all right
结果数量惊人。好了，我们
let's go ahead and get started now first
开始吧。首先，
thing that we want to do is set the
我们要将
project file to 32 bits per channel so
项目文件设置为每通道32位。
if you hold down alt you can cycle
按住Alt键可以在
through 8 16 and 32 bits this will just
8位、16位和32位之间切换。这样，
give us more color information when
在处理明亮发光的效果时，我们可以获得更多的色彩信息。好了，我们
effects all right so let's take our
把
Street sidewalk footage drop it into a
街景人行道素材拖进去。 新建一个
new comp and let's create a new solid
合成，我们创建一个新的纯色图层，暂且
we'll call this lightning hit okay and
称之为“闪电”。
then we're going to add the advanced
接下来，我们要添加高级
lightning effect so we could come over
闪电效果。我们可以在
here to the effects and presets we can
这里找到“效果和预设”，
type in lightning scroll down to
输入“闪电”，向下滚动找到“
advanced lighting and drop that on here
高级照明”，然后把它拖到这里。
now quick sidenote Video Copilot we've
顺便提一下，Video Copilot
developed a free tool called effects
开发了一个名为“效果控制台”的免费工具，可以
console that allows you to apply effects
让你更快地将效果应用
to layers a little bit quicker so I'm
到图层上。所以我
going to delete this and using the
要删除这个图层，然后使用
effects console that you can download
效果控制台（你可以
for free link in the description I'm
免费下载，链接在描述里）。我按下 Ctrl+空格键，输入“
going to type in lightning and then I
闪电”，然后
can hit enter and
按回车键，就完成了。
works just like that so you can use the
你可以使用
effects preset windowsill but throughout
效果预设窗口，但在整个
the tutorial I'll probably be using
教程中，我可能会使用
effects console now first thing I'm
效果控制台。现在，我要做的第一件事
going to do is go to the glow settings
是进入发光设置，将不
and turn the opacity down to zero I'm
透明度调到零。我
not a big fan of the glow and we're
不太喜欢默认的发光效果，我们
little bit later so let's focus on the
稍后会创建自己的发光效果。
core now let's turn the core radius up
现在，我们先关注核心。将核心半径调到
to maybe three make it a little bit
大约 3，让它稍微
thicker now remember we want the
粗一些。记住，我们希望
lightning to hit on the ground so what I
闪电击中…… 地面，所以我
can do is take the rectangle mask tool
可以用矩形遮罩工具在
and just draw a shape around the bottom
底部画一个形状。
so if I turn this off you can actually
如果我关闭这个遮罩，你可以
see that I've isolated this bottom part
看到我已经把底部隔离出来了。
and the cool thing is that the Lightning
很棒的是，闪电
effect can actually interact with it
效果可以和它互动。
so what we can do is go to the alpha
所以我们可以调整透明度（Alpha），
obstacle and just turn this up a bit and
稍微提高一下。
now you can see that it's sort of
现在你可以看到它有点像
touching the surface so we could bring
接触到地面了。我们可以把它移到
this down here now I can hit control
这里。现在我可以按 Ctrl+Shift+
shift H and that will hide the
H 来隐藏
controller's or the masks I can also
遮罩。我也可以在
just turn off the masks right here and I
这里关闭遮罩。我
can move this round but if I move it too
可以移动它，但是如果我把它移得
far one way it actually stretches off
太远，它会超出
the layer so what I can do is go down to
图层范围。所以我可以进入
the expert settings and we have a
高级设置，找到一个叫做“
setting called termination threshold so
终止阈值”的设置。
if we turn that down to about 5% and we
如果我们把它调到 5% 左右，
can see that it actually cuts off those
可以看到它确实切掉了
extra points and this way we have a
多余的点。这样我们的
perfect contact of our lightning now
闪电就能完美地接触到地面了。
there's a few other cool settings here
这里还有一些其他很棒的设置，
things like decay we can turn on decay
比如衰减。我们可以开启衰减
main core and this is a cool setting for
主核心，这是一个可以
varying the thickness a bit we can also
稍微改变闪电厚度的很棒的设置。我们还可以调整分叉。
play around with the forking I like to
我喜欢调整……
play with the turbulence and turn it
湍流，
down a bit it becomes more straight and
调低一点，它就更直了；
you turn it up it gets really complex so
调高一点，它就变得非常复杂。
about right there maybe turn up a little
差不多就在这里，也许可以稍微调高一点
bit of branching now another cool thing
分支。
I like to do is add some animation to
我喜欢做的另一个很酷的事情是给核心半径添加一些动画，
the core radius so we could keyframe it
我们可以用关键帧，也
or we could add a quick expression so
可以添加一个简单的表达式。
I'm just going to add a wiggle
我这里要添加一个摆动
expression so I'll alt click on the
表达式，按住 Alt 键点击
stopwatch next to the core radius and we
核心半径旁边的秒表，然后向下滚动，
type in and expression well do wiggle
输入表达式：`wiggle seven comma maybe three`。
seven comma maybe three and what this
这个
says is that seven times a second we
表达式的意思是每秒随机改变 7 次，每次改变
factor of three so this will just give
3 倍。这样，
the core if we look closely here just a
如果我们仔细观察，就会发现核心有一些细微的
little bit of variation
变化。
now there's another setting here called
这里还有一个设置叫做
the conductivity so as I move this sort
电导率，当我移动它时，
of undulates the electrical current now
电流会波动。现在
what we can do is alt click on that
我们可以按住 Alt 键点击
stopwatch and add another expression so
秒表，添加另一个表达式。
this time we'll use the time expression
这次我们使用时间表达式：`
so time star four times and maybe two
time star four times maybe two`。这个表达式会将
and this will just multiply time times
时间乘以
two and slowly change it as it goes now
2，并随着时间缓慢地改变它。
there's a lot of detail here maybe I'll
这里有很多细节，也许 我
turn the forking down just a little bit
稍微调低一下分叉，
maybe turn the decay down like I like
也许再调低一下衰减，
for them to touch down on the ground so
这样它们就能像我喜欢的那样落地，
that looks nice now the other thing we
看起来不错。现在我们还可以做的另一件事
could do is actually animate the
是给
direction now I should quickly point out
方向添加动画。我应该快速指出，
if you play around with the types you
如果你尝试不同的类型，
can actually create some slightly
实际上可以创造出一些略有
different looks
不同的外观，
breaking kind of creates some
比如破碎会产生一些
interesting sort of patterns and there's
有趣的图案，还有
some other interesting ones so play
其他一些有趣的效果，所以可以尝试一下。
around with that we'll probably just
我们现在可能只
stick to direction for now all right so
专注于方向。好的，
this is looking pretty good maybe we
看起来很不错，也许我们
could just add a little bit of movement
可以给方向添加一些运动，
to the direction set a keyframe and just
设置一个关键帧，然后
move it a little bit and of course you
稍微移动一下。当然，你也
can play around with the different
可以尝试不同的
settings as well the core drain will
设置，核心衰减会
create some interesting variation and
产生一些有趣的变化，
the fork variation as well so a lot of
分叉变化也是如此。
cool settings here that don't usually
这里有很多很棒的设置，但通常没有
get explored enough all right so we've
得到足够的探索。好的，我们现在
got this maybe we'll turn up the core
有了，也许我们可以稍微调高一下核心
radius just a bit all right so this is a
半径。好的，这是一个
great start now we can actually try to
很好的开始。现在我们可以尝试
make it look good
让它看起来更好。
so what we can do is precompose the
我们可以做的是预合成
Lightning layer so choose layer
闪电图层，选择图层
pre-compose move all attributes we will
预合成，移动所有属性，我们将其
call this lightening comp and hit OK now
命名为闪电合成，然后点击确定。现在，还有
one thing we should probably do is if we
一件事。 我们应该做的是，
double click on it we can open it up and
双击它就可以打开它，然后把
let's set the core color to maybe a blue
核心颜色设置为蓝色，
setting and we can hit tab and use the
我们可以按 Tab 键，然后使用
left arrow to go back or just go back to
左箭头返回上一级，或者直接返回到
the calm alright so now let's go ahead
默认设置。好的，
and create that nice reflection now if
现在我们来创建一个漂亮的反射效果。如果
we look back at the original example you
我们回顾一下之前的例子，
can see that the reflection contacts and
可以看到反射效果与周围环境相协调，并且有
there's nice specular highlights and
漂亮的镜面高光，而且
it's all procedural so it moves as the
它是程序生成的，所以会随着
lightening moves all right so let's
光线的移动而移动。好的，我们先来
start by creating a specular reflection
创建一个镜面反射。
so what I'll do is I'll duplicate the
我会复制
layer control V or edit duplicate and
图层（Ctrl+V 或编辑/复制），
then I'm going to solo that layer and
然后单独显示该图层，
effect now I can search for it or I can
接下来添加线性擦除效果。我可以搜索它，也可以直接输入“
just type it in linear wipe and what
线性擦除”。
this effect does is essentially just
这个效果本质上就是
it's like a transition effect so let's
一个过渡效果。我们把它
just set this to 180 and what I want to
设置为 180 度。我想做的是（
do and if I hold down control as I move
按住 Ctrl 键移动
it will move slower is I want to just
会减慢移动速度），我想单独
isolate the very bottom of this effect
显示这个效果的最底部，就像
just like that and that way I've created
这样。这样我就在
a highlight of exactly where the
最底部创建了一个高光。
lightning contacts the ground and now
闪电击中地面，现在
I'm going to add a blur so we're going
我要添加一个模糊效果。我们要
to add a box blur which is the latest
添加一个盒状模糊，这是
and greatest in the current version of
当前版本
After Effects and it's called the fast
After Effects 中最棒的模糊效果，叫做快速
box blur and I'm going to set the blur
盒状模糊。我将模糊设置
to horizontal and increase the blur
为水平方向，并增加模糊
radius and then I'm going to add another
半径。然后我要添加另一个
fast box blur and by the way you can
快速盒状模糊。顺便说一下，你可以
right click add to favorites and that
右键单击“添加到收藏夹”，这样
way it shows up at the top and this time
它就会显示在顶部。这次
I'm going to do a vertical blur so we'll
我要添加一个垂直模糊，所以我们把它
turn that up now here's the thing about
调高一些。现在要注意，
a blur if I blur it too much it fades
模糊效果如果过度，就会
out entirely so what I want to do is add
完全消失。所以我要添加一个纯色
a solid composite right now the
合成。现在
background is transparent
背景是透明的，
so I'm going to add a solid composite so
所以我要添加一个纯色合成。
it's called solid composite add that set
它叫做“纯色合成”，添加后将
it to black and you can faintly see our
其设置为黑色。现在你可以隐约看到我们的
glow or our blur right now but on top of
光晕或模糊效果。除此之外，
that I'm going to add an exposure effect
我还要添加一个曝光效果。输入“
so type exposure hit enter and now with
曝光”，然后按回车键。现在有了
the exposure effect I can turn this up
曝光效果，我可以把它调得
really bright and this is the nice thing
非常亮。这就是
about working in 32 bits per channel is
使用 32 位/通道的好处，它提供了
that you have more flexibility and color
更大的灵活性和更高的色彩
accuracy so now if I turn up this
精度。 如果我调高
vertical blur I can create a nice streak
垂直模糊，就能创建出漂亮的条纹。
now if you use a solid composite you no
如果你使用纯色合成，就
longer have an alpha Channel so let's
没有Alpha通道了，所以我们把
set this to additive and then turn on
它设置为叠加模式，然后打开
our lightening layer so now we can
增亮图层。现在我们可以
actually see what they look like
看到它们叠加
together but what I want to do is cut
在一起的效果了。但我想要做的是
off the top part of this blur and I can
切掉这个模糊的顶部，我可以
do that by adding another linear wipe so
通过添加另一个线性擦除来实现。
we could type in linear wipe set this to
我们可以输入“线性擦除”，再次将其设置为
180 again and bring the completion down
180，降低完成度，
and then turn up the feather just a
然后稍微提高羽化值。
little bit this way we give it a little
这样可以增加一些立体感。
now and we've got something going on
现在我们可以看看效果，已经有点效果了。
alright so this is a really good start
这是一个很好的开始。
now I want to start introducing a nice
现在我想在
texture into this effect as well so if
这个效果中加入一些纹理。
we go to the project I've got this
打开项目，我
grunge texture here and we could drop
这里有一个粗糙纹理，我们可以把
this into our scene maybe right on top
它拖到场景中，也许就放在
of the lightening maybe we'll hit return
增亮图层的正上方。我们按回车键，把
and we'll call this spec now if we turn
它命名为“高光”。现在如果我们
on our background plate or just unsolo
打开背景板或者取消独奏
all the layers things are looking pretty
所有图层，效果看起来很
good but the only problem with this is
不错。但唯一的问题是
that it looks too smooth so we want to
它看起来太光滑了，所以我们想
add a little bit of texture so that's
添加一些纹理。 纹理就是用来做
what this texture is for so if we turn
这个纹理的。如果我们
this on maybe what we'll do is make it a
启用它，我们可以把它变成一个
3d layer and we'll rotate it
3D图层，然后旋转它，
and just try to align it to the surface
并尝试让它与表面
a bit we could hit s and scale it up now
稍微对齐。我们可以按S键放大它。现在
I could probably do a 3d camera track on
我可能可以在背景上做一个3D摄像机跟踪，
the background but let's focus on the
但我们先专注于
lightening stuff and let's just go time
光照部分。我们先暂停画面，然后
and freeze-frame and we'll just work off
定格，暂时用静止帧来操作。
a still frame for now so I'll turn the
我启用
texture on and I'm going to pre compose
纹理，然后预合成
this I'm going to choose layer pre
它。我选择图层预
compose move all the attributes so we're
合成，移动所有属性。我们把
just going to call this ground texture
它命名为“地面纹理”，然后
and hit OK now I'm going to toggle the
点击确定。现在我切换
switches and we're going to take this
开关，将这个光照
lightening specular layer and set this
高光图层设置
to luma matte now if you look closely
为亮度遮罩。现在仔细观察，
the texture is now affecting that
纹理正在影响高光。好了，
got the first one done now what we could
第一个就完成了。现在我们可以给它
do is maybe we'll color coat this so
上色，把它
we'll just change this to red and the
改成红色，
texture to green and that will be a
纹理改成绿色，这样更
little easier to see so what I'm going
容易看清。 我要做的
to do is select these two and choose
就是选中这两个图层，然后选择“
edit duplicate and now I'll take this
编辑/复制”。现在我选择
bottom copy and I want to blur it out
下面的副本，我想让它
even more so I'm going to go to the fast
更模糊一些，所以我要进入快速
box blur the horizontal I'm going to
框模糊，水平方向的模糊值要
increase that and I'm going to turn out
增加，曝光度也要降低，
the vertical as well so what we're doing
垂直方向也要增加。这样我们就能
is creating more of a diffused
创建一个漫
reflection area and the whole trick to
反射区域。关键在于尽可能地还原
happens in reality where you have a
现实中的情况：一个
really bright spot with the specular
高光点非常明亮，周围环绕着
highlights and then you have a more
一个更柔和的漫反射
diffused softer area around it okay so
区域。好的，我们
we'll turn the background on so we can
打开背景，这样就能更好地
see this in context and this bottom one
观察效果。下面这个图层我们
will call this diffuse and maybe turn it
称之为“漫反射”，可以再增加一些。最后，
up a bit more and again we can soften
我们还可以柔化一下
the linear wipe at the end
线性擦除，让它看起来
just to create a more three-dimensional
更有立体感。好的，效果还不错，
but we're also going to need a couple
但我们还需要几个
more we need a really hot spot for the
图层，我们需要一个高光点来表现
contact so let's take the specular and
接触面。所以我们选择高光纹理
texture and duplicate it ctrl D and
图层，复制它（Ctrl+D），然后把
we'll call this point and this is going
这个图层命名为“点”。这个点会稍微……
around the contact so what we'll do is
接触点周围的柔化效果，所以我们接下来要做的就是，把
let's see we'll turn the vertical one
垂直方向的模糊
down and turn the side one up a bit and
调低一点，把侧向的模糊调高一点，
then we can turn the exposure down this
然后降低曝光度。这就是
is sort of how we control it so very
我们控制它的方法。我们可以大致
roughly we can see what's going on here
看看效果，
and maybe turn the intensity down a bit
也许可以把强度调低一点，再加
and we can add a little bit of vertical
一点垂直方向的模糊，这样
but that looks nice
看起来不错。
and maybe even take the specular you can
甚至可以把镜面反射的不
turn the opacity down on them now and
透明度调低，
that's a easy way to mix it in in
这是除了使用曝光效果之外，一种简单的混合方法。效果相当
so that's pretty good maybe we'll want
不错，也许我们想要一点
to have like a little bit of a contact
接触
point so we could do even one more copy
点，所以我们可以再复制一次（
ctrl D and this time we'll keep the blur
Ctrl+D），这次我们要把模糊度调得非常非常
really really small then we can you know
小。然后我们可以
disable the background we can see this
禁用背景，可以看到这里好了一些。虽然为了
seem like a lot of work just for this
这
little reflection but it really makes a
点反射效果做这么多工作看起来有点多，但它确实能显著
big difference in the realism if you can
提升真实感。如果
actually have interaction now if you
你现在
want to see more shiny could lower the
想要更闪亮的效果，可以降低
horizontal blur and they'll kind of make
水平方向的模糊度，这样看起来会更亮一些，
it look a little shinier and even turn
甚至可以把这
these two down so just sort of a matter
两个值都调低。就这样。 这有点像是在
of playing with the look and of course
尝试不同的效果，当然也要
looking at real reference but obviously
参考真实的素材，但很明显，现在
that looks really nice and here's the
看起来很棒。
cool thing is if I lock this window open
更酷的是，如果我锁定这个窗口，打开
up the lightning any one of the
任意一个
lightning columns
闪电元素，把
slide it over to the side here closing
它拖到旁边，然后关上它，
is I could go and I can change the color
我就可以去更改颜色了。比如，
so we could change this to gold and
我们可以把它改成金色，
everything will update come back over
所有东西都会更新。回到
here close that alright so we'll turn
这里，关上它。好了，现在我们
our background back on you know we can
重新打开背景。你知道，我们现在
even just grab just the Lightning comps
甚至可以只选择闪电合成。
now and that's why I like to use the
这就是我喜欢用
color because you can right click on the
颜色的原因，因为你可以右键点击
color and choose select label color and
颜色，选择“选择标签颜色”，
it will just select all of those and I
它会选中所有这些元素。我甚至可以把其中
could even just move some of these
一些
things up so I could grab the lightening
元素向上移动，所以我可以选中闪电，把
move this up even scale it down if I
它向上移动，如果需要的话还可以缩小它。
want to but I'm not bringing the texture
但我不会移动纹理，
I'm leaving the texture where it is so
我会把纹理留在
that it stays locked to the ground so
原地，这样它就能固定在地面上。这样效果很好。好了，
that's pretty good all right so I think
我觉得
that looks pretty good for our
我们的
reflection and as you saw earlier we can
反射效果看起来很不错。正如你之前看到的，我们可以稍微
play around and tweak it in a little bit
调整一下。
but now let's take a look at adding the
现在我们来看看如何给
glow to our lightning so let's take our
闪电添加发光效果。 把我们的
lightning bring it up to the top here
闪电效果放到最上面，
and let's set it to additive all right
然后把它设置为叠加模式。好的，
so now let's go ahead and start working
现在我们开始处理闪电的
on the glow effect for our lightning all
发光效果。
right so here's how I like to work with
我喜欢这样处理
my illuminated effects so what I'm going
光照效果：我要
to do is add a solid composite effect
添加一个纯色合成效果，
and set this to black now it's additive
并将其设置为黑色。现在是叠加模式，
so it shouldn't make a difference and
所以应该不会有什么区别。
now we're going to add a glow effect and
接下来我们要添加一个发光效果，将阈值调到
threshold down to zero and the intensity
零，强度
down extremely low and the radius to
调到非常低，半径调到
about 25 or 30 we want to be really
25或30左右，我们要非常非常非常
really really low and then we're going
低。然后我们要
to duplicate the glow and we'll increase
复制发光效果，并增加
the radius because we want to really
半径，因为我们想要
have a nice soft glow so increase the
一个柔和的发光效果，所以将
radius about 100 or so and then one more
半径增加到100左右。然后再次
time we'll hit control D and duplicate
按下Ctrl+D复制。
so now we've got three glow effects
现在我们叠加了三个发光效果，
stacked on can increase that a bit now
可以稍微增加一下。现在效果差别
it's not making that big of a difference
不大，
so what I'm going to do is add an
所以我要添加一个
exposure effect now and now I can
曝光效果。现在我可以
increase the exposure effect and this
增加曝光效果，这样
will create a nicer result so even
会产生更好的效果。 虽然
so many stacked effects you can actually
叠加这么多效果会稍微慢一些，但实际上你可以
get a much softer looking glow now the
得到更柔和的光晕。
other thing I could do is add a hue and
我还可以添加色相和
saturation effect so we'll type in hue
饱和度效果，所以我们输入“色相
and saturation add that and
和饱和度”并添加。在
before the exposure I could just turn
曝光之前，我可以稍微
the saturation down just a touch and of
降低饱和度。
course I could probably just do this on
当然，我也可以对
the actual lightening effect as well so
实际的光照效果进行调整，比如
I could perhaps go inside of the
我可以进入
lightening and maybe change the color to
光照效果内部，将颜色更改为
something else like maybe blue go back
其他颜色，例如蓝色。
alright so this is a really great start
好的，这是一个
to creating some nice lightening now
创建漂亮光照效果的绝佳开端。现在
I've also included this hotspot element
我还添加了一个热点元素，
that you can bring in and set this to
你可以将其导入并设置为“
additive and this is just kind of fun
叠加”。这
for creating source we could just use a
对于创建光源来说很有趣。我们可以使用
curves adjustment to just dim it down or
曲线调整来降低它的亮度，
even colorize it and just link it up we
甚至为其着色，并将
could link it up to the position but
其链接到位置。
kind of get the idea just kind of cool
大致了解一下，
to see it come from a source now here's
看到它来自光源的感觉很酷。现在还有
a couple of other cool things so again
一些其他很酷的东西。再次强调，
now that you see the glow and you start
现在你看到了光晕，并开始
to understand the intensity of this
理解这种
lightening effect you might think about
光照效果的强度，你可能会想……
highlight effect a bit and it doesn't
稍微调整一下镜面高光效果，你会发现
seem as crazy to have such a large area
这么大面积的光照看起来也没那么奇怪，我们
we just fuse that a bit you know here's
只需要稍微融合一下。这里还有
one more cool trick again it's all about
一个很棒的技巧，关键在于
the combination of effects but as an
效果的组合。比如
effect called turbulent displace and if
湍流置换效果，如果
you switch this to horizontal
你把它切换到水平
displacement kind of creates this
置换，就能产生左右
side-to-side movement well what you can
移动的效果。你可以
do is turn the size down to zero I think
把大小调到零（我记得
it's two and then the complexity up to
是2），然后把复杂度调到
say two or three and if you increase the
2或3。如果你增加
amount you see that it creates like just
数值，你会发现它会产生
a little bit of displacement just like a
轻微的置换，
little bit of an unevenness as if the
就像
surface were you know a little rocky
表面有点不平整一样，比如
maybe like three and then you can play
3。然后你还可以尝试
around with the the blur effects so but
模糊效果。不过
you might think yourself too you know
你可能也会想，
you don't have time to render a
你没有时间渲染
turbulent displacement effect and I
湍流置换效果，我
understand that too
理解。
now the cool thing about this is that
这个效果的妙处在于
it's all procedural and it's all being
它是程序生成的，而且全部都
generated from the same lightening layer
来自同一个光照层。
so again we can change the color of the
所以我们可以改变光照的颜色，
update on the other side it's all about
另一侧的效果也会随之更新。 关于如何更
working smarter and more efficiently you
聪明、更高效地工作，你
know I can remember in high school my
知道，我记得高中时，我
parents would ask me to do some yard
父母会让我做些院子里的
work and what I would do is I would pay
活儿，而我做的就是花钱雇
the neighbor kid to beat me up and then
邻居家的小孩揍我，这样
my parents would see my face and you
我父母就能看到我的脸，你
know so I got out of it at least until
知道，这样我至少可以逃到
the next day and then I'm out there
第二天。然后我就顶着一只
sweeping the porch with like a black eye
黑眼圈
and a sprained shoulder so I bought some
和扭伤的肩膀去扫门廊了。所以
time is what I'm saying all right so
我说的就是，我争取了一些时间。好了，
we've got this lightening effect here
这里有个光照效果，
I've changed the color to more of like a
我把它的颜色改成了更像
gold color and now I want to show you a
金色的颜色。现在我想向你展示
couple of different ways to make it look
几种让它看起来
more realistic so for example if we
更逼真的方法。例如，如果我们
select the main lightening effect here's
选择主要的光照效果，这里有
a couple of cool things you can add to
一些很酷的东西可以添加进去。
it one is it turbulent displace
一个是湍流置换，就像
so just like before we could turn the
之前一样，我们可以把它的
size really low and look at this it just
大小调得很低，你看，它会
kind of creates kind of a random noise
产生一种随机的噪点。
and we could maybe put that before the
我们可以把它放在
glow effect and just turn it down really
发光效果之前，把它调得很
low just just make it look energetic
低，让它看起来更有活力。
and this just gives it more texture now
这让它更有质感。除此之外，还有
on top of that there's a really cool
一个很酷的
effect called vector blur and I think
效果叫做…… 矢量模糊，我想
you guys know this effect it's been
你们都知道这个效果。 等等，
overused once or twice by me I'll admit
我承认我之前确实用得有点过头了，
but if we can just tone it down a little
但如果我们稍微降低一下强度，
bit we might be onto something now we
或许就能找到一些效果。现在我们
can turn the amount up to about three or
可以把数值调到
four and maybe the ridge up a bit so
三四左右，也许还可以把脊线也调高一点。我们来
here let's see if we turn this up high
看看把这个调高一点怎么样。这个效果
okay and this can be really cool you can
真的很酷，你可以
put it after some of the effects so this
把它放在一些特效之后。
is what you don't want I think I think
我觉得你不应该这样。我觉得
if you just kind of give it a little bit
只要稍微调整一下，就能保留
and so that way you still have some hard
一些硬
edges but there's also some soft edges
边，同时也能有一些柔和的边缘。你可以
and just play around with the order if
尝试不同的顺序。如果把它
we put this before the exposure effect
放在曝光效果之前，
it's going to change entirely the look
画面会完全改变，
of it but it's also kind of cool if it's
但如果放在之前也挺酷的，这样
spots around the Lightning so just keep
闪电周围就会有一些亮点。所以要保持
it subtle and even the displacement
微妙，甚至置换效果也
could be put to after and these two
可以放在之后。这两个
effects actually can kind of work
效果其实可以配合使用，
together so one of them takes the detail
一个效果会
away and the other sort of adds it back
减少细节，另一个效果则会补充细节。
now another thing I like to do is add a
我喜欢做的另一件事是给
little bit of randomness to the
亮度添加一些随机性，让它
brightness and flicker it and so we
闪烁。所以我们
could actually add a wiggle expression
可以添加……
into the exposure and perhaps wiggle
在曝光中调整抖动表情，也许可以调整到
maybe like seven comma four so I don't
7 到 4 左右，这样
mind if it gets really bright like that
即使它变得很亮也没关系，
I just want to make sure it gets bright
我只是想确保它能快速变亮。
really fast so let's set this to like
所以我们把它设置成
nine and three
9 到 3 左右，这样就
so that's pretty good now one last cool
很好了。最后一个很棒的
tip for creating a more interactive
技巧是，要创建更具互动性的
reflection is to use our source material
反射效果，可以使用
in our ground texture so let's take our
地面纹理中的源素材。所以我们打开
street footage layer and copy edit copy
街道素材图层，复制、编辑、复制，
and then jump inside of the texture and
然后进入纹理图层，把
what we can do is just paste it in here
它粘贴到这里（
edit paste control V and let's set the
编辑、粘贴、Ctrl+V），并将
transfer mode to soft light and that way
传输模式设置为柔光，这样
it just interacts with it a little bit
它就能与地面纹理产生一些互动。
and maybe we'll get rid of this and
也许我们可以去掉这个图层，然后
let's add an exposure effect and what we
添加一个曝光效果。我们
want to do is just softly introduce some
想要做的就是柔和地引入一些
of the brightness from this texture I'm
来自这个纹理的亮度。我
here and that's pretty good let's go
这里正在观察人行横道，效果很好。我们
back here and so now it actually changes
回到这里，现在它确实发生了
it just a little bit so if we turn off
一些变化。如果我们关闭
the background you can actually see the
背景，你就能看到
way that it's interacting and what we
它的互动方式。我们可以
might do is lock that open up the
锁定它，打开
texture slide it over and just you know
纹理，把它拖过来，然后…… 现在，
just play around with if we could add a
我们可以尝试增加
little more contrast to it and this kind
一些对比度，这其实
of makes sense because in some cases the
很有意义，因为在某些情况下，
white paint might be a little bit
白色油漆可能
smoother than the ground and so you just
比地面更光滑一些，所以增加一些
create a little bit more variation which
变化就能
just helps make it look more realistic
让它看起来更逼真。虽然只是个小细节，
so small thing but anytime you can
但只要你能将
introduce your source material into the
源素材引入
simulated effects it's going to look
模拟效果中，效果就会
that much better now if you remember the
好得多。如果你还记得
effect from earlier where it looks
之前的效果，
almost like the lightening is moving in
闪电看起来就像是朝着
a direction sort of a reverse gravity
某个方向移动，有点像反向重力
effect here so there's actually a really
效果，那么实际上有一个非常
interesting and simple way to do this so
有趣且简单的方法可以实现这一点。
if we just go back to our example we
让我们回到之前
created let's open up the Lightning comp
创建的例子，打开闪电合成。
now in order to get this to work what
为了让它生效，我
I'm going to do is hit ctrl R and bring
要按 Ctrl+R 并
down a guide
添加一个参考线，
and this will tell us where the cutoff
这将告诉我们
point is for our reflection all right so
反射的截止点在哪里。好的，
to create this directional traveling
为了创建这种定向移动的
Lightning effect what we're going to do
闪电效果，我们要
is create a new solid and we're going to
创建一个新的纯色对象，并将其高度设置为高于
make it higher than the normal size so
正常值，比如
we're going to make it say 2048 and
2048，
that's because we want it to move
因为我们希望它
vertically so I'm going to add more to
垂直移动。 我要增加
the height but if I wanted to move
高度，但如果我想
side-to-side I can make the width higher
左右移动，可以增加宽度，
so hit OK
所以点击“确定”选择
ideal layer and we're going to add the
理想图层，我们要添加
Lightning effect turn the glow settings
闪电效果，将发光设置
down to zero and I'm going to move the
调到零，然后我要移动
position of the layer so I'll hit P set
图层的位置，所以我按 P 为
a keyframe for the position I'm also
位置设置关键帧，还要
going to set a keyframe for the origin
为原点
and the direction and the idea here is
和方向设置关键帧。我的想法是，
I'll move this up and then I'll take
我先向上移动这个图层，然后找到
these two points will move this one here
这两个点，把这个点移到这里，再把
and I'll move this point just somewhere
这个点移到
where we can track so maybe about right
我们可以追踪的位置，大概就在
there in between these two points now
这两个点之间。
because we want this to interact with an
因为我们想让它与
alpha Channel I'm also going to create a
Alpha 通道交互，所以我还要创建一个
mask so we'll create a mask right at the
遮罩，在与之前图层相同的位置创建一个遮罩，
same point as our other one and we'll go
然后找到
to the alpha obstacle crank that up that
Alpha 障碍物，把它调高，
looks good and I'm also going to hit M
看起来不错。我还要按 M
for the mask path and set a keyframe
选择遮罩路径并设置关键帧。好的，
okay so now if I select the layer hit
现在如果我选择图层，点击“确定”，
you I should have four keyframes so I
应该有四个关键帧：
have the path for the mask the origin
遮罩路径、原点
and direction and the position of the
、方向和
layer so what I'm going to do is first
图层位置。那么，接下来呢？ 首先，我们把
let's set the mask down to none just so
蒙版设置为“无”，这样
we can see the size of the layer
我们就能看到图层的大小，
otherwise it hides that so if we just
否则它会被隐藏起来。如果我们把
turn it off we could see it will move
它关掉，就能看到它会
forward and I'm going to move the layer
向前移动。我要把图层
down and what we need to do is offset
向下移动，然后我们需要把
these values back up so let's move this
这些值向上偏移。所以我们把它移回原来的
back up to where it was
位置，把
this up move the mask back up to our
蒙版移回大约这个位置的
cutoff point about there and then we'll
截止点，然后再
turn the mask back on so now if we look
打开蒙版。现在我们
at this we've created a traveling
来看，我们已经创建了一个移动的
Lightning effect now it might be a
闪电效果。可能有点难
little hard to see so I'll just extend
看清，所以我延长
the length of the comp and then just
合成的长度，然后
shift these keyframes over and let's
移动这些关键帧，看看效果。
moving down now I should probably lock
现在你应该能看到它正在向下移动。我应该把
that position right there so let's so
这个位置锁定在这里。
the cool thing is that there is a little
很棒的是，它有一定的
bit of movement but just not too much
移动，但又不会太大，
you get a feel for the direction of the
你可以感受到
lightning now we could change the type
闪电的方向。现在我们可以改变闪电的类型，
some of these other ones like strike are
有些类型，比如“雷击”，
they move we could turn the turbulence
移动方式更稳定一些。我们可以降低湍流，
down all the same settings will work and
所有设置都一样。 这样就能
create some different interesting
创造出一些有趣的
results we can still play around with
效果。我们还
the direction as well so we could have
可以调整方向，让它左右
it sort of shifting from side to side
移动，
but the start point is still going to
但起点仍然保持
stay the same now if you wanted to
不变。如果你想让它看起来像是
create this coming out of somebody's
从某人
hand you could create a horizontal layer
手中伸出来，可以创建一个水平图层，操作基本相同。
check this out we'll set the size up to
看看这个，我们把大小设为
like 4 turn the that's good and then
4，这样就很好了，然后把
also the color to like I don't know blue
颜色设为蓝色，我们来
and then let's take a look so maybe we
看看。也许我们
just darkened down the color of it now
只是把颜色调暗了。现在
we don't have to change all of our look
我们不需要更改所有的外观
settings
设置了。好的，现在我们来看看动画效果，看起来像是要
what looks like animating into the
渗入
ground so pretty cool we can select the
地面。很酷！我们可以选择
keyframes and then go up the animation
关键帧，然后向上选择“动画
keyframe assistant reverse keyframes and
关键帧助手”，再选择“反转关键帧”，
now it will play the other direction so
现在它会朝另一个方向播放，就像是从
sort of sucking out of the ground
地面吸出来一样。
execute ah does you know yeah so now at
啊，你知道吗？是的。
controlled now through just opacity so
现在，所有这些参数都可以通过不透明度来控制，这很棒。
you can tweak the look to kind of go
你可以调整外观，使其与
with the color that you've chosen and
你选择的颜色相匹配。
alright so there you have it directional
好了，这就是定向
lightning alright so for this next
闪电。接下来，
section we're going to take a look at
我们将学习如何
using a lot of really cool tricks so the
使用一些非常酷的技巧来创建云层下方的云层效果。其
idea is that there's a light source that
原理是，
exists behind the clouds and it's
云层后面存在一个光源，它会
creating this sort of illuminance effect
产生这种光照效果。我们将
so what we're going to do is take this
使用一段普通的
plane smoke footage drop it into a new
烟雾素材，将其放入一个新的
comp and this is just very plain footage
合成中。这段素材非常普通，我们先来
just to give it a little bit of a
添加一些
texture let's first create our light
纹理。首先，
source so we'll create a new solid and
我们创建光源。创建一个新的纯色物体，并将其
we'll call this light it okay and we're
命名为“光”。好的，我们将
more time at least one more time and
再次添加闪电效果，至少添加一次，并将
we'll set the opacity of the glow down
发光的透明度设置
to zero now for this one I'm going to
为零。这次，我将
try the Omni lightening and this just
尝试使用全向闪电，它会
kind of creates a more sort of sporadic
创建一种更加零散的
moving lightening so I think that's kind
移动闪电效果，我觉得这
of cool let's animate the conductivity
很酷。接下来，我们来制作导电
state and just move it around so I just
状态的动画，并让它移动。我
set a keyframe hit you we can see those
设置了一个关键帧，你可以看到这
two keyframes so just kind of give a
两个关键帧。稍微调整一下即可。
little movement I'm also going to go to
移动方面，我还要去
the core settings and add a wiggle
核心设置里，给核心半径加一个摆动
expression to the core radius
表达式，
so wiggle I don't know like eight and
摆动值大概是 8 和
six and so what that's going to do is
6，这样它就会像闪烁一样忽明忽暗。把
turn the turbulence down so we decay and
湍流调低，让它衰减，
yeah that's that's what we're trying to
没错，这就是我们想要的效果，
do we just want to have it kind of
我们只是想让它有点
flickering and flashing a bit might even
闪烁，甚至可以把
turn the core radius down and that way
核心半径调低，这样
it'll turn off more often cool so let's
它就会更频繁地关闭。酷！我们把
set the core color to say a gold color
核心颜色设为金色，再
and let's add a solid composite so solid
添加一个纯色合成，纯色合成，颜色
composite set that to black all right so
设为黑色。好的，效果不错。
that's working pretty well now I want to
现在我要
go ahead and pre compose this effect so
预合成这个效果，所以
I'll choose layer pre compose just call
我选择图层预合成，把它命名为“
this light comp and hit OK now we're
光合成”，然后点击确定。现在我们要在
this so we're going to add a fast box
这个基础上添加一些效果，所以我们要添加一个快速盒状
blur now this is kind of the reverse of
模糊。这跟
what we just did so actually want to
我们刚才做的正好相反，所以我们要
start out with a really wide blur now it
先做一个非常宽的模糊，让它逐渐
fades out so again we'll boost that
淡出。所以我们再次增强
within exposure effect okay now I want
曝光内效果。好的。 我想
to
增加一些细节，所以
I'll do is maybe lower this down nice
我要做的就是降低这个
soft glow is I'll do a CC composite on
柔光效果，然后在上面做一个CC合成，
top of this right so effect Channel CC
也就是效果通道CC
composite set this to additive right so
合成，设置为加法，这样
we're sort of putting it back on top and
我们就把它放回顶部了。
then I'm going to add another box blur
然后我要再添加一个盒状模糊，
this one also pretty soft like you see
这个也很柔和，就像你看到的，我们
we're sort of doing an inverse and I'm
做了一个反向操作。
also going to take I'll just add these
我还要添加这些，再做一个
I'll do another exposure effect and then
曝光效果，然后
I'm going to do another CC composite so
再做一个CC合成，也就是
do channel composite will set this to
通道合成，设置为
add and we'll add one more box blur
加法，再添加一个盒状模糊，好了。我的
there we go so the idea is to kind of
想法是
create a very diffused looking light
创建一个非常漫射的
source unlike the previous sort of
光源，与之前的
scenario so I'm just playing around with
场景不同。我只是在尝试不同的
the exposure effects so something like
曝光效果，大概就是
that okay all right so this is our
这样。好的，这就是我们要在
deep within the clouds so what I'll do
云层深处看到的照明效果。所以我要
is come over here to the project and I
切换到项目窗口，为
want to create a mask for the clouds so
云层创建一个遮罩。
what we have is this smoke sprite so
我们有一个烟雾精灵，
bring this out and what I can do is
把它拉出来，
duplicate it set it to lighten and I can
复制它，设置为变亮，然后…… 可以
move it off and so it kind of blends
把它移开，这样它就能很好地融入背景，既不会让画面
with it it doesn't make it brighter and
变亮也不会让画面
it doesn't make it darker just sort of
变暗，只是自然地
blends with it nicely and I can rotate
融合在一起。我可以旋转它（
this hit the W key rotate it scale it up
按W键），也可以旋转、
or down and duplicate it again and so
缩放，还可以再次复制。所以
we're just going to sort of try to move
我们现在要随意移动
these
这些
pieces around randomly until we fill the
元素，直到填满
entire screen now one thing to note is I
整个屏幕。需要注意的是，我
want to try to keep some pockets of a
想保留一些
dark area and that way there's bits of
暗区，这样就能对
sort of occlusion for the light so let's
光线起到一定的遮挡作用。所以我们
just distribute this around a bit and so
稍微分布一下这些暗区，这样就能营造出
we do want little areas of dark pockets
一些暗区，对吧？
right okay so now we're going to take
好的。现在我们要选中
all of these smoke elements hold down
所有这些烟雾元素（按住Shift键
shift will select them all and we'll
即可全选），然后进行
pre-compose these now I'm going to go
预合成。现在我要
inside here and I'm going to create an
进入这个图层，创建一个
adjustment layer and here we'll add a
调整图层，并添加
curves adjustment try that okay so we'll
曲线调整。试试看。好的。
go back now we've got this texture we
现在我们有了这个纹理，
should probably name this let's name
应该给它命名，就叫它“
this a smoke mask so what we want to do
烟雾蒙版”吧。我们要做的
is we want to occlude parts of the light
是，
with this texture so we'll take this
用这个纹理遮挡部分光线。 所以，我们选择这个
light comp and we'll use the set mat
光合成图层，并使用“设置材质”
effect and this allows us to select a
效果。这样我们就可以选择
texture in this case the smoke texture
纹理，这里我们选择烟雾纹理。然后，
we'll change the mat from alpha to
我们将材质从“Alpha”改为“
luminance so now it looks something like
亮度”。现在看起来是这样的。
let's click invert and now let's set
点击“反转”，然后
this layer to additive so now if we look
将此图层设置为“叠加”。现在，我们来看一下，
at this we're starting to get a feel for
开始感受到
that sort of inverted look now let's
这种反转效果了。接下来，我们再
play with the Alpha channel a bit more
调整一下Alpha通道。
let's add a curves adjustment switch
添加一个曲线调整，
over to the alpha Channel
切换到Alpha通道，
and maybe we'll add a solid composite on
然后在该通道上方添加一个纯色合成图层，将
we'll make it black and now we can color
其设置为黑色。现在，我们可以使用
correct it with a curves adjustment so
曲线调整进行颜色校正。这样可以更
that just makes it a little easier to
轻松地进行
color correct it or maybe instead of
颜色校正。或者，
curves we just do an exposure effect
我们也可以不用曲线，直接使用曝光效果。
sometimes it's easier to work with
有时，
exposure when you're dealing with light
处理光线时，使用曝光效果会更容易。效果很不错。
so that's pretty nice I can see a little
我看到
bit too crisp of an edge and I might
边缘有点太锐利了，我可能会稍微
soften that just a bit but I like the
柔化一下。但我喜欢这种
sort of randomness of it and now we
随机感。现在，我们
could do a curves adjustment on top of
可以进行曲线调整。 除此之外，我们还可以
everything and just give it a little bit
稍微调整一下
of gamma just a little bit more contrast
伽马值，增加一点对比度。
of course we could add a glow effect on
当然，我们还可以添加一个发光效果，这样就能
top of this and that will create an even
营造出一种
more sort of light scattering type of
更强的光散射
effect so pretty cool type of effect and
效果，非常酷炫。
you know we have another tutorial for
我们还有一个关于次
doing like subsurface skin uses some of
表面皮肤的教程，它运用了一些
the same principles but this idea of
相同的原理。这种
visualizing the negative space really
可视化负空间的方法确实
helps to sell the depth of a shot and of
有助于增强画面的深度感。
course we can now go into the source
当然，我们现在可以进入源
material for this and potentially you
素材，
know make some changes to this maybe
进行一些修改，比如
fill in some of the gaps and things like
填补一些缝隙
that so it feels a little bit more flush
等等，让画面看起来更平滑。另外，
change the opacity you could create a
调整不透明度可以创建
few different depths so a lower opacity
不同的深度，较低的不透明度
will just create
会
less pockets and then another
减少凹陷。还有一个
interesting thing that we could do is we
有趣的技巧：我们
could take all the layers here go to the
可以把所有图层都放到开头，
beginning hit our set a keyframe for the
设置一个旋转关键帧，然后放到结尾，
little bit of rotation then and now if
稍微旋转一下。现在
we watch this the clouds will almost
观察一下，云朵看起来就像在
movement to them and we could of course
运动一样。当然，我们还可以
add other things like turbulent
添加其他效果，比如湍流
displacement but I think we've used that
置换，但我认为…… 今天我们已经用得够多了，
enough today yeah not too bad
嗯，还不错。
see all that crazy glow exposure
看看那些疯狂的光晕和曝光
adjustment doesn't seem so crazy now all
调整，现在看起来没那么疯狂了。
right and again in the light comp I
好的，在光合成里，我
could duplicate this and I could offset
可以复制这个效果，
the conductivity so it's random set it
然后偏移导电性，让它随机变化，设置
to add this is a mini tutorial so sorry
为添加。这是一个迷你教程，所以抱歉
for the sidetrack but I could set this
跑题了。我可以把它设置
to blue and then if I go back you've got
成蓝色，然后如果我返回，你就能看到下一个
the next hot template file available now
热门模板文件了，售价
for 1995 I'm just kidding all right so
1995美元。我开玩笑
third-party plugin but what I want to
的。好吧，显然这个教程里的信息太多了，所以我们再添加一些内容。我们要创建一个新的纯色图层，并将其命名为“e 3D”。我们要打开Element，这是一个第三方插件。但我想向
show you is how you can use lightning to
你展示的是如何使用闪电效果与之
interact with it so whether you have a
交互。无论你有一个
logo or something like that this is
logo还是其他什么东西，这都是
going to be a really cool technique for
一个很酷的
getting that interactive lightning so
实现交互式闪电效果的技巧。所以我们来
let's create some text you think I'd
创建一些文本。你可能觉得我应该已经
have like a preset ready but here we are
准备好一个预设，但这里没有。
alright I'm going to create a text layer
好的，我要创建一个文本图层，
will go to turn that off on the element
然后把它关闭。  Element
3d layer will load up a custom text
3D 图层会加载
element of the Video Copilot
Video Copilot 的自定义文本元素，
and then we'll launch the scene setup
然后我们启动场景设置。
alright so we're going to create some
好的，我们要快速创建一些
quick 3d text going to click the extrude
3D 文本。点击挤出
button and that's going to load the
按钮，它会加载我们
custom path that we just selected of the
刚刚选择的徽标自定义路径。
logo and we'll jump over here to the pro
我们切换到 Pro
shaders metal and let's just throw one
Shaders Metal 材质，这里就放一个出来。
out here and sometimes people ask like
有时有人会问
what is element 3d for and well it's for
Element 3D 是做什么用的，它就是用来
stuff like this like creating really
创建像这样的
cool fast text so let's just click on
炫酷快速文本的。我们点击
the material and we can play with the
材质，就可以在
extrusion settings here and one thing I
这里调整挤出设置。我
like to do is double up the extrusion
喜欢做的一件事是把挤出值加倍，
and then click on the second one expand
然后点击第二个挤出值，扩展
the edges increase the extrusion and
边缘，增加挤出量，
then use like like a darker metal color
再用一个更深的金属色，就像
on it like that now I could go see
这样。现在我可以看看，
alright that's pretty good
嗯，效果不错。
another thing you could do is select a
你还可以选择一个
model go to the UV settings and you can
模型，进入 UV 设置，
increase the repeat so if you do like
增加重复次数。比如
two by two it just will increase the
2x2 的重复次数，就能增加
detail now this top one I think that's a
细节。我觉得上面的这个
little bit too reflective I'll just do
有点太反光了，我再调整一下。
something a little bit more diffuse and
漫反射，
you can also select the materials and
你也可以选择材质并
edit them so I can make it more diffused
进行编辑，比如我可以
by scrolling down turning the glossiness
通过向下滚动降低光泽度来增加漫反射效果，
down it looks pretty good now I'm going
现在看起来很不错。我要
to load up a different environment map
加载一张不同的环境贴图，比如
maybe just like an outside looking one
一张室外环境贴图，
that looks pretty good
看起来也不错。
so back to this material let's turn the
回到这个材质，我们
reflectivity down a bit to and I'll just
稍微降低一下反射率，让它更
kind of make it a bit darker so there we
暗一些。好了，
go
经典的金属文字标志，点击。好了，就是这样。
by turning on the enhanced multi
通过启用增强多重
sampling and let's create a camera so to
采样来清理一些边缘，然后我们创建一个摄像机。在
layer new camera look at thirty
图层“新建摄像机”中选择“
five-millimeter and then we'll switch to
35毫米”，然后切换到
the camera and move forward now another
摄像机并向前移动。现在
thing I'm going to do is turn on the
我还要启用
ambient occlusion
环境光遮蔽，
so I'll table that switch it to raytrace
所以我把它切换到光线追踪，
and that looks pretty nice now to give
看起来很不错。现在为了让它看起来更
it kind of a flashy look I'm going to
闪亮，我要
create a couple of lights maybe point
创建几个光源，比如点
lights and we'll do like oldest dude
光源，我们用
some orangish color lines and we'll
一些橙色的线条，把
stick them over here so half rez that's
它们贴在这里。半分辨率，效果不错，
pretty good and we want these to sort of
我们希望它们看起来像是在
be flashing kind of on and off so we
闪烁。 开关，所以我们
could go to the intensity alt click on
可以调整强度，按住 Alt 键点击
the stopwatch and we'll add an
秒表，然后添加一个
expression wiggle if you like six and
表达式抖动，比如 6 到
like four hundred like a lot and then we
400，很多，然后我们
just duplicate it a few times I mean not
复制几次，我的意思是不要太
too many times but but anyway you get
多次，总之你应该明白我的
the idea you're basically just trying to
意思了，你基本上就是想
lighting with the scene I like to play
为场景创建一些交互式光照。我喜欢
around with the environment this is like
摆弄环境，这对于
a big thing for element is just being
Element 来说很重要，因为它
able to shift the reflection to sort of
能够调整反射，使其与
match what you're working on it kind of
你正在处理的内容相匹配，或者说与
what you're going for so and you can
你想要的效果相匹配。你
also like animate it so like slowly
还可以给它添加动画，比如让
animate the reflection something like
反射缓慢移动等等。
that alright so now here's a really
好了，现在这里有一个非常
important sort of workflow tip when
重要的工作流程技巧，当
you're working with
你处理
rendered layers and that's essentially
渲染图层时，那就是
to select the things that make up that
选择构成
element title and pre-compose them and
元素标题的内容并预合成它们。
that way After Effects will manage the
这样 After Effects 就能更好地管理渲染，
rendered you won't have to keep re
渲染完成后你就不必反复重新
rendering it and particularly for
渲染了，特别是对于
effects like lightning or I'm going to
像闪电这样的效果。或者，我要
get rid of some of this blue I have to
去掉一些蓝色，
it's too blue so now if I want to add
它太蓝了。现在，如果我想添加……
some interactive lightening what I can
一些交互式光照效果。我
do now is create a new solid call this
现在可以创建一个新的实体，称之为“
lightening and we'll add the advanced
光照”，然后添加高级
lightening effect so I think I've shown
光照效果。我想我已经向
you good ways to create the glow and
你们展示了创建发光效果的好方法，
stuff so let's talk about how to get it
现在我们来谈谈如何让它
to interact so what you want to do is we
交互。我们需要做的是
want to set the channel for the Alpha
设置标题的 Alpha 通道。
choose set matte and we can select the
我们可以选择“设置遮罩”，然后选择
3d title and what that does is takes the
3D 标题。这样做会将
Alpha Channel from the title and
标题的 Alpha 通道
replaces it in the solid and then of
替换到实体中。
course the advanced lightening effect
当然，高级光照效果
will interact with the Alpha Channel so
会与 Alpha 通道交互。
we could turn the Alpha obstacle up and
我们可以提高 Alpha 障碍物的数值，
now you're getting a nice little bit of
现在你会看到一些不错的
movement now the other interesting thing
动态效果。另一个有趣的地方
is that this effect also will calculate
是，这个效果还会计算
if the Alpha Channel is blurred so check
Alpha 通道是否模糊。
this out if we add a channel blur put
看看这个：如果我们添加一个通道模糊，把
that above the lightening and just add a
它放在光照上方，
little bit of blurriness you see how the
稍微增加一点模糊度，你会看到
lightening sort of diffuses in a very
光照以一种非常
cool way so let's say we set the
酷的方式扩散开来。假设我们将
lightning from directional to
光照从定向光设置为
a two-way strike and that way we have
双向光，这样我们就有
two points to control maybe we set this
两个控制点，也许我们可以将其设置为
to a gold color just imagine the
金色。 想象一下
beautiful glow that we've created
我们之前创造的美丽光晕，
previously but now we have a great thing
现在我们拥有一个很棒的功能，
where we can animate this across the
可以让它在整个标志上动起来，
logo and we have controls over sort of
而且我们还可以控制
the softness of it and and now it's
它的柔和度。现在，
going to animate no matter what so
无论如何它都会动起来。
here's another kind of example like
这里还有另一个例子，
let's say we want to animate the
假设我们想让角色动起来，
characters and do something fun with it
做一些有趣的事情，
we could go to the multi object right so
我们可以进入多对象模式。
for every group there's a multi object
每个组都有一个多对象
setting and what this does is sort of
设置，它的作用是将
breaks every piece down to an individual
每个部分分解成单独的
piece so we can rotate the Y so a lot of
部分，这样我们就可以旋转 Y 轴，有很多
settings but once you kind of get the
设置选项。一旦你
hang of it you could just do like a cool
掌握了它，你就可以制作一个很酷炫的
slick keyframe that brings the
关键帧，让
characters kind of into place or even
角色就位，或者像这样，
I see like a wot X displays
我看到一个 X 轴显示得
nice okay let me go back and because
很好。好的，让我回去。因为
it's the Alpha Channel it's going to
它是 Alpha 通道，
stay up to date so all we have to do is
所以它会保持更新，我们只需要
animate the origin in the direction in
以一种有趣的方式让原点朝某个方向动起来，
an interesting way which is not always
这并不总是
obvious but there's a lot of fun to be
显而易见的，但
had with this I think this is something
用这个功能可以玩出很多花样。我认为这是
that I haven't even really explored
我以前从未真正用过的东西。 已经探索得
enough but whether it's the Alpha
够多了，但无论是 Alpha 版本的
obstacle but then playing around with
问题，还是尝试各种
the you know the type of forking and
分支之类的功能，
really cool capabilities with this
这个插件都有很多非常酷的功能。
plugin so I know this doesn't look
我知道它现在看起来并不
amazing but you kind of get the idea of
惊艳，但你应该能明白我的意思，它本质上就是让插件
just essentially having it feel like it
感觉像是在进行
interacts and that just adds so much now
交互，这大大增加了它的实用性。
in this case I just put a copy behind
在这个例子中，我只是在 logo 后面放了一个副本，让它看起来更丰富一些。
more depth and feel like it's
深度感和互动感，让它们感觉像是
interacting in the same theme so
在同一个主题下，所以
sometimes that's a cool trick if you
如果你
want something to feel like it's wrapped
想让某个东西感觉像是被包裹着，那么在它
around it have stuff that renders behind
后面渲染一些东西，这有时是个很棒的技巧。
it as well alright so obviously there's
好的，显然
a lot of different things that we can do
我们可以朝着不同的方向做很多不同的事情，
it and that is where I will leave it for
这就是我想留给
you guys to take some of these different
你们的，让你们借鉴这些不同的
ideas and see what you come up with I'd
想法，看看你们能创作出什么。我
love to see some of the different stuff
很想看看你们的作品，
if you guys want to send it to me tweet
如果你们想的话，可以发给我，或者发到推特上。
it to me I always love to see what
我一直很喜欢看
people are doing with some of these
大家如何运用这些
techniques and as always combine them
技巧。和往常一样，把它们
with other tutorials with other ideas
和其他教程、其他想法
with your own ideas and let's keep this
以及你们自己的想法结合起来。让我们继续
thing going let's not break the circuit
下去，不要中断！
alright everyone thanks so much for
好的，谢谢大家的
watching hopefully learn some cool
观看，希望你们能学到一些很棒的
techniques and as always be sure to
技巧。和往常一样，记得
check us out on Video Copilot
在 Video Copilot.net、Instagram、Twitter 等平台上关注我们。大家好，
great stuff hi I'm Andrew Kramer and we
我是 Andrew Kramer，我们
will see you next time
下次再见。
[Music]
[音乐]